Okay, so, in this video, I'm going to be showing you how to set up your local development
environment on macOS or Linux.
In the next video, we'll be setting up your development environment on Windows, but the goal
of both will be the same.
We want to set up Git so that we can use GitHub and eventually GitHub pages in order to host
your projects online for free.
As well as installing Visual Studio Code so that we can write and organize our code on
our computer, instead of using something like CodePen.
Okay, so let's get started.
The first step on macOS or Linux is going to be to install Homebrew.
I'll provide a link to this within the course, but the website is simply brew.sh.
So what this is, is it is the missing package manager for macOS.
The only thing we need to do is paste this code into our terminal on Mac and let it run,
and it will basically allow us to use brew install and then whatever package we want.
In our case, we're going to be installing Git, but you can use it to install a lot of
different packages online.
Okay, so first things first, we're going to copy this code here, and next, we're going
to use command spacebar, and we're going to type in terminal to open up our terminal window.
So I'm going to make this a little bit bigger, and I'm going to zoom in as well on the font,
okay, and we'll just slide that into view here, all right, perfect.
Okay, so now I'm going to use command V, and I'm going to paste in my code here, and
then I'm just going to press enter, and it's going to check for my password.
So I'm going to type in my password here, and then I'm going to press enter, and it's
telling me all the things that it's going to do.
So you'll see that it's going to install brew, homebrew, a few other things, and all
this, great, and I'm going to press enter because I want to install homebrew, and we'll
just wait and let this finish.
Okay, so you might have noticed mine maybe took a little bit longer than yours did, but
that is because I have X code installed, so it might be a little bit quicker, and it might
look a little bit different, but in the end, eventually you will be back to your name at
iMac, and then you can type again in the terminal.
So once you can type again in the terminal, that's how you know that it is complete.
All right, so we're going to go back to our browser here.
So now that we're done with homebrew, we're going to go to the git web page.
So again, I'll provide a link for this, but basically this is the instruction to download
git for macOS.
So the first option here is to install homebrew, if you don't have it already, of course
we just did that, and then we simply type this simple command brew install git.
So that's what we're going to do next.
So we're going to go back to our terminal here, and we're going to type brew install git
and press enter.
Okay, and that's done as well again, once you can type, that means it's done, and we're
going to just make sure that it's working, we're just going to type git dash dash version,
press enter, and you can see that it is working version two point three seven point one.
Perfect.
Okay, so we're done with our terminal, we can close that now, and we're going to go back
to our browser here, and we're going to go to the visual studio code website code dot
visual studio dot com, and you can see that when I land on this page, it already knows
which operating system download Mac Universal, so I'm going to go ahead and click on that,
and you'll see that the download should get started, and we can see that it's downloading
here.
Okay, so now we can go ahead and open the file, and we can see now we actually have
our application here, so if I click on this now, you'll see that it's going to open visual
studio code, it actually doesn't need any setup, we need to confirm that we want to open
it, and here we are, we're in visual studio code, and this is actually a sneak peek of
a project we're going to make later on in the course.
Okay, so we have visual studio code installed, and we have git installed as well.
So you can skip the next video, because it's going to be about the Windows setup, but
after that we're going to look at setting up visual studio code itself, including some
basics about that, as well as some visual studio code extensions, and then we have a few more
topics to cover in this module.
All right, that's it for now, I'll see you in the next one.